Guide to the Stanford University, Department of English, Honors Theses
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives.
Stanford University, Department of English, honors theses
circa 1967-2014
SC4-3891
Stanford University. Department of English.
16.25 Linear feet (395 volumes in 20 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Department of English.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was transferred to the Stanford University Archives by the Department of English in 1989 and 1993, and from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Information about Access
The collection is open for research; material must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Department of English.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Department of English.; English literature--Study and teaching.; Student papers.
Collection Contents
- Theses, pre-1986
  - Abrams, Steven, Imagery and character in Macbeth: a play of action.., April 15, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Alden, Patricia, The comic vision in James Joyce's Ulysses., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Alley, Henry, Milton's Adam and Samson: The Growth within the Architecture., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Alison, The Diary of Anais Nin: Discovery of the woman and the writer.., 1975 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Brian, Style and personality in The Blood Oranges: A phenomenological approach to the fiction of John Hawkes.., 1975 (Box 1)
  - Aries, Jane Ellen, Proust/Joyce the word and the World., 1968 (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Jamie, William Blake's The Gates of Paradise: the power of the imagination., 1970 (Box 1)
  - Barnes, James, Alienation and action in Tennyson's Maud., 1975 (Box 1)
  - Baskette, James R., To define is to distrust. The monogenetic comedy of Sterne and Beckett., 1966 (Box 1)
  - Bean, John C., The concept of love in Hemingway's major fiction before 1941., 1965 (Box 1)
  - Bevan, Ernie, Beneath the surface; multi-vision in Giles goat-boy., 1970 (Box 1)
  - Bledsoe, Cathy, The Journey Home., April 26, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Bliss, Lee, The grotesque in modern southern fiction: a study of selected works by William Faulkner, Flannery O'Connor, and Eudora Welty., 1965 (Box 1)
  - Block, Bruce, The modern fool: a study of fools and madmen in Catch-22., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Bowes, Diana, Virginia Woolf's Women in Marriage., 1982 (Box 1)
  - Braunmuller, Jr., Albert R., The structural function of plot and character in Ben Jonson's Alchemist., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Kenneth A., The Works of Richard Scowcroft., April 5, 1983
  - Brown, Laura, Jane Austen: the man and his work., March 15, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Buhler, Susan, Love and Marriage. the individual and society in the novels of Jane Austen., 1969 (Box 1)
  - Bunyan, John, Perspective in Women in love: Wayne Booth, Henry James, and the imaginative process in novel-writing., 1975 (Box 1)
  - Callahan, Connie, Tennessee Williams and Edward Albee: Man's predicament in the modern world., April 17, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Cameron, Scott, The struggle for expression: a study of Mormon literature., 1970 (Box 2)
  - Cannon, Peter, A case for Howard Phillips Lovecraft., April 16, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Carlton, Sara, George Herbert: an approach to his ideas on style through his reading of Saint Augustine., 1963 (Box 2)
  - Carrell, Jennifer, Opening Enchanted Doors to the Good: The FAir Folk in Modern Fantasy., March 23, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Chilcott, John, The Road Back to Flux in Henry Miller's Tropic of Cancer., March 23, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Chittendon, John, The tragedy of a first love in Chaucer's Troilus and Criseyde and Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet., 1970 (Box 2)
  - Christensen, Jane P., Mark Twain's development of the one-man crowd scene., 1965 (Box 2)
  - Cioffi, Grant, Industiralism, isolation,a nd loss of artistry in Winesburg, Ohio., April 16, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Claycamp, Leslie Suzanne, Fitzgerald, money and women., 1974 (Box 2)
  - Clayton, Clarissa, Hemingway's Imagery: Perfection and Disintegration., 1982 (Box 2)
  - Cohen, Walter, The involute structure of Vladimir Nabokov's fiction., March 9, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Crandell, Ashley, Notes on Milton's Paradise Lost., April 17, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Crow, Nora, Jonathan Swift: The techniques of second person satire.., 1965 (Box 2)
  - Cutler, Debra Joan, Patterns for a new genre: literary journeys ataken by adults and children., 1975 (Box 2)
  - Davis, Karen, Children in the Fall of Faulkner's South., 1982 (Box 2)
  - Deveney, Karen, Vladimir Nabokov's Lolita: the secret of durable pigments., 1965 (Box 2)
  - DiBattista Maria, The Penitential Way., 1969 (Box 2)
  - Diehl, Sarah J., Louise Bogan: An Autobiography in Verse., 1982 (Box 2)
  - DiNapoli, John, Rhetoric and response int he fiction of Aldous Huxley., 1966 (Box 2)
  - Donovan, Margaret C., Myth and Demystification in the Works of Sean O'Casey: A Study of the Dublin Trilogy., 1982? (Box 2)
  - Douglas, Christine, Kingsley Amis: The anti-romantic., 1975 (Box 2)
  - Dryden, Lanny M., The craft of Graham Greene's fiction: Narrative technique in seven novels., April 16, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Edinger, Bill, Samuel Johnson: the streaks of the tulip., 1963 (Box 2)
  - Fagan, Julie, O, Matter and impertinency mixed!: How familial, sexual, and social pressures generate madness in the novels of William Faulkner., 1975 (Box 2)
  - Fam, Samia, The Frustration of Significance: Dowell's Experience with Knowledge., 1980 (Box 2)
  - Fam, Samia, The Search: A Reading of Absalom, Absalom! and The Moviegoer., 1981 (Box 2)
  - Forward, Jr., Robert H., The Novels of Nathanael West. A critical study.., 1966 (Box 2)
  - Fraser, Christie, The way the wind blows; an essay on Wallace Stevens., Spring 1971 (Box 2)
  - Friedlander, Anne R., Women in Little dorrit., 1967 (Box 3)
  - Galbraith, Tom, The fantasy element in satire: an exploratory essay., 1966 (Box 3)
  - Garvin, David L., The English Lyric from Chaucer to Wyatt., 1969 (Box 3)
  - Gavin, Cristina Miles, A Sense of Eternity., March 23, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Gilbertson, Catherine Jo, The Sot-Weed Factor: history re-invented`., 1971 (Box 3)
  - Gilinsky, Armand, Visions of immortal love: the art of Vladimir Nabokov., 1975 (Box 3)
  - Ginsburg, Gerald N., Gnawing through the thongs and bull-hides: ancient sources for modern verse., 1969 (Box 3)
  - Gioia, Michael Dana, "We Had Always Dwelled Together". The pattern of self-pursuit in Poe., April 16, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Glann, Hilary, Towards a New Definition of the Novel in the Sixties: The Fictions of Richard Brautigan and Kurt Vonnegut., April 4, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Glaser, John P., Vitality of poison; Lord Byron and experience of nothingness., April 15, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Goodfellow, William S., Shakespeare's Henry V.., 1967 (Box 3)
  - Goodhue, Susan, A Study of the Aesthetics of Roger Fry and Virginia Woolf., May 12, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Goodrich, Tom, The mythology of the weather in Wallace STevens., 1969 (Box 3)
  - Gostovich, John, Post-modern fiction: the example of the American war novel., 1970 (Box 3)
  - Gould, Stephanie, literary symbolism in the modern world., 1967 (Box 3)
  - Gregg, Stephen, Probing the Abyss: Class and Character in Forster's Howards End., April 26, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Grossman, Richard, The resurrection of Raskolnikov., 1965 (Box 3)
  - Gunesch, Douglas L., James Joyce: Cycologist and Creator. (Box 3)
  - Haley, Paul, The landscape of the mind in Beckett's Molloy., 1966 (Box 3)
  - Harris, Duncan S., In desperate defiance: Thoreau as radical idealist., 1965 (Box 3)
  - Harrison, Antony, The creative world: a study of the novels of Joyce Cary, including an analysis of The horse's mouth., 1970 (Box 3)
  - Harrison, Beth, "Bad Dreams" in Katherine Anne Porter's Fiction., 1982 (Box 3)
  - Heineman, Alan, J. D. Salinger: an appreciation at midpoint., 1966 (Box 3)
  - Henderson, Celia, The Defence Convention in Verse Satire., 1982 (Box 3)
  - Hendrickson, Steven W., The love poems of Fulke Greville., 1964 (Box 3)
  - Herbert, William, Two generations of Romantic Poets: Increased Skepticism about the Ability of the Imagination to Perceive Objectively., April 2, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Herold, Patricia, The Ocean metaphor: a process of fluidity in four novels of Virginia Woolf., 1975 (Box 3)
  - Hess, Linda, A solitary perfectionist: Yvor Winters and literary criticism in the twentieth century., 1964 (Box 3)
  - Hodge, Michael B., Religion and psychoanalysis in Theodore in Roethke's poetry., April 16, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Howe, Georgiana, Faulkner's As I lay dying: an American comedy., 1963 (Box 3)
  - Hutt, Katherine, William Carlos Williams, Spring and All: Painting with Words., April 22, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Jablow, Betsy, Variations in narrative form: shandeism and the modern novel., 1967 (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Roberta E., The Game-Element in Three Middle English Metrical Romances., 1968 (Box 3)
  - Kahn, Judith, Petrus Alfonsi: "qui miscuit utile dulci" in his Disciplina Clericalis., June 1984 (Box 7)
  - Kaku, Jennifer, The Fate of Innocence: the child figure in English Literature., 1981 (Box 3)
  - Kast, Barry S., Forms of Salvation: REgressive Imagery in the Poetry of Theodore Roethke., 1968 (Box 3)
  - Kaye, Howard J., Satiric method in Aldous Huxley and Evelyn Waugh., 1964 (Box 3)
  - Keeran, Sally, Anna Stessa's rise to notice: a linear look at woman in Finnegan's Wake., April 17, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Kempson, Judson Norris, Historical Narration as self-definition, Quentin Compson and the legacy of the Old South., March 1983 (Box 3)
  - Kime, Wayne R., Nathaneal West's dreamless worlds: Miss lonelyhearts, A cool million, The day of the locust., 1963 (Box 4)
  - Klapper, Lianne, Profane Love and Divine Meditation: Contraries Meet in the Poetry of John Donne., April 3, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Kommers, Tom, The Four Zoas., 1969 (Box 4)
  - Kotz, Steven J., Tamburlaine the Great and the Development of Eponymic Comedy., 1968 (Box 4)
  - Kronman, Craig, Ambiguity in Gerard Manley Hopkins' middle sonnets: a linguistic criticism., 1975 (Box 4)
  - Krupa, Gene, The evolution of ben Jonson's world-view: a study of five of the comedies., 1965 (Box 4)
  - Kugelmass, Joel N., The sea crimson, or setting sail from byzantium: Joyce's Ulysses., 1967 (Box 4)
  - Lamphere, Vicki, Three odes of John Keats., March 23, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Larson, Karin, Why I like Keats., April 15, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Laub, Susan, A discussion of the criticism of Byron's Don Juan from 1819 to the present., 1975 (Box 4)
  - Lavine, Stephen David, The less deceived: Philip Larkin and the Movement., 1969 (Box 4)
  - Lavis, Elaine Kay, Obscurity in the poetry of Edwin Arlinton Robinson., 1963 (Box 4)
  - Lazaroff, Jr., Thomas A., The Road to "Autumn": Toward an experiential Poetry. (Box 7)
  - Lazer, Hank, Blake's handbook for the imagination; (the theme of creation in Blake's poetry thRough 1795).., April 15, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Lee, Felicia A., Lily Briscoe: Virginia Woolf's Self-Portrait in To the Lighthouse., April 26, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Leedy, David, Image and Idea: The Poetry of Yvor Winters., 1969 (Box 4)
  - Lewand, Kathy, The fate of innocence and child narratives in Faulkner., 1975 (Box 4)
  - Lewin, Jeff, Sylvia Plath: the development of her art., 1967 (Box 4)
  - Little, Mark Wallace Vischer, Time and Titan: A Study of Wyndham Lewis., 1969 (Box 4)
  - Littlefield, Lynn, Elements of romaticism in Henderson the Rain King by Saul Bellow., 1975 (Box 4)
  - Low, Charlotte, Malory: A study in style., 1965 (Box 4)
  - Mack, Elizabeth Flood, The Dubious Heroes: A Study and Comparison of Romaticisim in Lord Jim and innocence in Absalom, Absalom!., 1980 (Box 4)
  - Maillard, Page, "The Woman is a Stranger": A Study of the Heroine in Jean Rhys's Novels., 1982 (Box 4)
  - Makepeace, Anne, The elliptical approach to identity in Franz Kafka's "Conversation with the Supplicant" and Samuel Beckett's Molloy, Malone Dies, and the Unnamble., 1969 (Box 4)
  - Martin, Dell H., The tiger of wrath, the jackel of lust: Reading Day of the Locust and Miss Lonelyhearts., 1968 (Box 4)
  - Matheny, Ed, George Bernard Shaw's philosophy of art., 1975 (Box 4)
  - Matsui, Connie, Women and the Victorian ideal: Dickens, Trollope, Eliot., 1975 (Box 4)
  - Maxeiner, Tom, The poetry of Yvor Winters., 1966 (Box 4)
  - McClure, Kerin A., Self-knowledge gained through discovery of positive ancestral history: a solution to bourgeois oppression in the novels of Toni Morrison., April 20, 1983 (Box 4)
  - McCoy, Richard, Samuel Beckett's Novels., 1968 (Box 4)
  - McCreary, Mary E., Henry James' In the cage: a study of romantic folly., 1963 (Box 4)
  - McElhany, Myrna L., Sin, heredity and knowledge: the conflict between religion and science in The scarlet letter, Elsie Venner, and The damnation of theron ware., 1963 (Box 4)
  - McInnes, Marion K., Walt Whitman's poetry: Aspects of the style., April 18, 1973 (Box 4)
  - McKinney, Shelly, Fact and Fancy: An analysis of the Sisters in Jane Austen's Works., 1981 ? (Box 4)
  - McMillan, James, Tin-Protoporphyrin induced suppression of total bilirubin formation and hyperbilirubinemia in adult male wistar rats with common bile duct ligation., June 9, 1986 (Box 4)
  - McMullen, Bruce, Thom Gunn and the heroic gesture., 1974 (Box 4)
  - McNally, Catherine Lineburgh, "A Wond'rous Lovely Storm": The Celebration of tragedy in Three Novels by Willa Cather., May 28, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Merrill, Annie, Roaming with a hungry heart: the journey in the fiction of Paul Bowles., March 23, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Metzger, Vivian, Perspectives on the Pst and present: an examination of William Faulkner and Heinrich Boll., April 2, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Meyer, Regula, The function of family relationships in Henry James' international novels: a study of The American, The Portrait of a Lady, and The Golden Bowl., 1981 (Box 4)
  - Min, Kelly, Appearances versus reality: the role of the disguised heroine in Shakespeare's comedies., 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Montgomery, David J., On Alienation, Freedom, and Salvation: Doestoevsky's vision of anarchy and apocalypse in The Possessed., April 13, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Morris, Marilyn Louise, Two villonauds: Ezra Pound and the outlaw-bard., April 15, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Mow, Shannon Sue, Renaissance stoicism and the work of Fulke Greville., Spring 1971 (Box 4)
  - Moynes, Jon, An approach to Sir Gawain and the Green Knight., 1968 (Box 5)
  - O'Meally, Robert G., Jean Toomer - black apostle., 1970 (Box 5)
  - Olcott, Anthony C., The author's special intention: a study of The real life of Sebastian Knight., March 8, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Olsen, Janeen Ann, How Shakespeare's comic heroines were created., 1974 (Box 5)
  - Ortiz, Ricardo, "All eligible to all": A Consideration of Walt Ahitman's Philosophical Method (with specific reference to the poet's study of Hegel)., March 17, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Parkinson, Lois, A procession of shadows: the reality of the characters in Virginia Woolf's The waves., 1996 (Box 5)
  - Parks, Donalisa, Extraordinary people: Children and "Moral Sense" in the works of Henry James., 1981 (Box 5)
  - Patrick, Susan E., E. E. Cummings: The Artistic Vision., 1968 (Box 5)
  - Pavlis, Timothy, The dimensions of myth in Absalom, absalom!., 1965 (Box 5)
  - Phelps, David S., Choosing Between the Woman Hero and the Heroine., February 22, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Price, Jr., John S., Jonathan Swift and the breaking of the circle., 1967 (Box 5)
  - Pridgeon, James, Scratches on the wall; classicism in Faulkner's novels., 1970 (Box 5)
  - Ransom, Daniel J., Noes on the endings of the Canterbury Tales., April 16, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Ravits, Martha, Fundamentals of Sexology or the Love Passion; in James Joyce's Ulysses., April 17, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Reed, William A., Of dreams, merchants, and kings.., April 16, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Ride, Sally, The "special providence" in Hamlet and The Tempest., April 16, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Robb, Christina, Ego dormio et cor meum vigilat: William Langland in Piers plowman., 1967 (Box 5)
  - Roberts, Nancy, A time of such quality: poems on loss by Thomas Hardy and Eugenio Montale., 1975 (Box 5)
  - Rosenthal, Ellen, Felaweshipe in the Pardoner's Tale: Aspects of Chaucer's use of liturgical parody and literary allusion., June 10, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Rotham, Lynn, The Progression from a solitary revolt to one of solidarity in the works of Albert Camus., April 15, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Rubinstein, Dorothea, An author and her art: a study of Ivy Compton-Burnett., 1966 (Box 5)
  - Salvatore, Burce, History in the short fiction of Nathaniel Hawthorne., 1965 (Box 5)
  - Sammons, Todd H., The Morality of Stylistics: An examination of classical and puritan rhetoric in Paradise Lost., April 16, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Sandler, Susan, Broken poetry: William Carlos Williams and the Conditions of Form. (Box 8)
  - Savery, Pancho, The waking dream: the process of individuation in Pound's Cantos., April 17, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Schwarberg, Ann E., The Route to Reconciliation: God, Man and society in The Scarlett Letter., 1982 (Box 5)
  - Scott, John S., Faulkner's moral vision., 1965 (Box 5)
  - Scott, Tim, Win lose or draw: the relative achievement of Ike McCaslin in Faulkner's "The Bear" and Go Down Moses., 1981 (Box 5)
  - Seidler, Tor, Lawrence and Elliott: morality and personality., April 17, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Selmi, Michael, The ideals of youth: the young intellectual in modern literature., March 18, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Sewall, Lori, She: love and the concept of woman in the poetry of Theodore Roethke., 1970 (Box 5)
  - Shatford, Sara, The Banishment Plays., 1968 (Box 5)
  - Shell, Marc, On change and exchange., 1968 (Box 5)
  - Sherline, Reid, Moments of True Feeling: Towards a reassertion of self over linguistic tyranny in the plays and novels of Peter Handke., April 26, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Siegfried, Charles, The function of doubt in early English tragedy., 1965 (Box 5)
  - Siminoff, David, Mrs. Dalloway - screenplay based on the novel, Mrs. Dalloway by Virginia woolf. (Box 8)
  - Siskin, Clifford Haynes, The Prelude: Books I, II, and IV., April 17, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Slotnick, Linda, Relativity for the millions: the science fiction of Lawrence Durrell., 1964 (Box 5)
  - Slovic, Scott, Indirect autobiography: A phenomenological introduction to the personal essay, fictional narrative, and confessional poetry as modes of self-expression, (Prolegomenon to a fuller study of Loren Eiseley, Jack Kerouac, and James Wright)., March 18, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Smith, David S., Vladimir Nabokov and mnemosyne., 1977 (Box 5)
  - Smith, Glenn K., Death and verbal regeneration in Dylan Thomas., 1966 (Box 5)
  - Spaeth, Nicholas, Seize the fire - a study of the innocence of William Blake., April 17, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Staton, Jana J., The private universe of Pale fire., 1965 (Box 6)
  - Steinberg, Majorie, A Comparison of Cervantes and Sterne., 1968 (Box 6)
  - Stephens, Janet, Redemption and comedy: From Tristia to Gaudium in Shakespeare's Non-tragic Drama., March 11, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Stephens, Susan, The development of the grail as a theme in medieval and modern literature., 1965 (Box 6)
  - Stevens, Laurie A., Rebellion in The Scarlet Letter., April 10, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Stinchcomb, Patricia, The redemption of the non-romantic heroine., Spring 1973 (Box 6)
  - Stockman, Henry, The architecture of "The Temple": a discussion of Herbert's collection of poetry., 1975 (Box 6)
  - Stone, Eugene R., John Keats and the egotistical sublime., April 16, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Strong, John, Lolita: An exemplification of artistic communication., 1970 (Box 6)
  - Sweigert, Elizabeth Anne, The wanderers Henry Adams and Henry james between worlds., April 6, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Tanner, Scott S., Alienation in the Life and Art of Thomas Hardy., April 6, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Thurber, Bart, The graceful moment: a study of The waves in relation to Jacob's room, Mrs. Dalloway and To the lighthouse., 1970 (Box 6)
  - Tonies, Trinidad L., The personal, the political, and the poetic: Adrienne Rich in process., 1982 (Box 6)
  - Treder, Jeffrey D., Howards end and the saving remnant of Matthew Arnold., 1963 (Box 6)
  - Tyson, Molly, Theseus., 1974 (Box 6)
  - Van Oss, Mark T., Reflections on Society: Families in Bleak House., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Veitch, Jonathan, Faulkner and Bergson: "The Palm at the End of the Mind"., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Visser, Katrina, Mothers and Others, Mothers and Daughters in the novels of Jane Austen, Charlotte Bronte, and Virginia Woolf., 1982 (Box 6)
  - Walker, Mark A., The influence of the tall tales on William Faulkner., 1963 (Box 6)
  - Wall, John Joseph, Jr., Mr. Twain and the South: with particular emphasis on The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn, Pudd'n'head Wilson, and Life on the Mississippi., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Weatherhead, Andrea, From Pan to Beethoven: The Develpment of E. M. Forster's Musical Symbolism., Winter 1983 (Box 6)
  - Wentworth, Mary C., Paving the way for Einstein's sister: science fiction by women: The Dispossessed by Ursula K. LeGuin, The Sirian Experiments by Doris Lessing, Woman on the Edge of Time by Marge Piercy., May 1983 (Box 6)
  - Wheeler, Cynthia A., Autobiography into art: F. Scott Fitzgerald's Tender is the Night., April 19, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Wilborn, William F., A study of David Jones' In parenthesis., 1966 (Box 6)
  - Williams, Helen, A study of the bourgeois woman in twentieth century literature., 1970 (Box 6)
  - Williamson, Craig B., Lolita: the unsung seduction., 1965 (Box 6)
  - Wiltsee, Elizabeth, this dust of words; a senior honors thesis: samuel beckett., 1970 (Box 6)
  - Winkes, Ken, Myth and the Romantic notion of time., 1968 (Box 6)
  - Woods, Majorie Curry, The Language of Djuna Narnes' Nightwood., 1969 (Box 6)
  - Wormhoudt, Daniel T., Richardson's religion and Clarissa., 1967 (Box 6)
  - Wright, Linda J., Songs of re-creation and revolution: contemporary black women poets., April 17, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Yamaoka, Julia, The death of Rachel and the birth of Benjamin: the mystical quest for divine unity in the Middle Ages., 1974 (Box 6)
  - Yeager, Robert F., Metrical variations in The Canterbury Tales: an interpretation., 1970 (Box 6)
  - Yount, Elizabeth, What will suffice: the consolation of Wallace Stevens., 1966 (Box 6)
  - Zadra, Gina M., The forms and structure of self-discovery in James Merrill's The Changing Light at Sandover., March 19, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Zweip, Mary, A study of ironic and low mimetic tragic novels: he who is violent and victimized, or she whose lover is beyond her grasp., April 20, 1972 (Box 6)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-1993-088
  - Archer, Elizabeth, Tess Durbeyfield: Not So Simple Dairymaid., May 1991 (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, Patricia, The Fate of Forster's Liberalism in Howards End.., May 1987 (Box 1)
  - Banks, Gabrielle, Chicano Fiction: The Exploration of Space in American Literature., May 1991 (Box 1)
  - Beattie, Lisa, Wedded Women: An Exploration of Female Identities in Eudora Welty's Delta Wedding., May 1988 (Box 1)
  - Berry, Julie, Issues of Gender and Sexuality in Marie de France's Lanval., April 1989 (Box 1)
  - Beyreis, Mark, The Gaudy Splendor of the Past: Carnival in William Faulkner's The Hamlet and Absalom, Absalom!., May 1988 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Bruce D., The Historical Incongruity of David Jones: In Parenthesis and the Great War., May 1988 (Box 1)
  - Bruck, Matthew H., Laughing at the Grotesque: a reading of Flannery O'Connor's stories., May 1988 (Box 1)
  - Carter, Kristen, Desire, frustration, and possibility in Virginia Woolf's Between the Acts., 1987 (Box 1)
  - Chin, Douglas, The Compromised Artist: Hardy's Censorship of Jude the Obscure., May 1988 (Box 1)